aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Vicious prisoners escaped from the Space Prison of Sargasso, and have begun their planetary galley.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들이 혹성 사냥을 개시했다
In order to protect the peace of Earth, Brave Seijin of the Space Police granted these brave heroes powers.
지구의 평화를 지키기 위해 우주 경찰 기구의 브레이브 성인이 힘을 부여한 용자(勇者)들
Their name is Dagwon.
그 이름은 다그온
Now, a new comrade has joined them.
그들에게 지금 새로운 동료가 가담했다
-Let's take root in that place right now!
-OK!
-어서 저곳에 뿌리를 내리자
-OK
Infinity...
무한...
Got it!
네~
Feel the might of the Infinity Cannon!
무한포의 위력을 똑똑히 보거라!
The Name is Gunkid
그 이름은 건키드
Mechanical Plant Mekaju Seijin
Appears
기계식물 메카쥬 성인
등장
You bastard!
이자식!
Damn!
젠장!
Star Burn!
스타 번!
Futile! Futile!
소용없다!
What a formidable weapon!
저거 참 엄청난 무기구만!
We're not going to win from the front!
정면으로 붙어선 승산이 없겠어
I agree!
동감입니다
We're not going to be alright if we get hit by that directly.
저걸 직격으로 맞았다간 아무리 우리가라 할지라도 무사하지는 못할 겁니다
Hey, what's the meaning of that?
이봐, 그게 무슨 뜻이야?
We might die. That's what I mean.
죽을지도 모른다는 뜻입니다
What? Don't be ridiculous!
뭐야? 웃기지마!
Dag Wing isn't being ridiculous!
다그 윙은 틀린 소리를 한 게 아니야
You should be a little bit pragmatic!
조금은 현실적으로 생각해 봐라
Damn!
젠장!
Dear gentlemen of Earth,
지구의 제군
I am Mekaju Seijin.
나는 메카쥬 성인이다
Do not come near me.
나에게 접근하지 마라
I will root in this planet and grow.
난 이 별에서 뿌리를 내리고 성장할 것이다
For that purpose, I'm simply taking nourishment of this planet.
그러기 위해서, 이 별의 양분을 흡수하는 것 뿐이다
Do not interfere.
방해하지 마라
What?!
뭐라고?!
Don't come near me, and you all will be fine.
접근하지만 않으면 된다
I will not give you gentlemen any harm.
나는 제군들에게 위해를 가하지 않을 것이다
But if you decide to interfere, this Infinity Cannon will not forgive you.
하지만 만약 방해를 한다면 이 무한포가 용납치 않을 것이다
That guy is getting bigger and bigger!
저자식, 점점 더 성장하고 있어!
It already grew more than 50 meters!
벌써 높이가 50미터는 되겠구만!
It's a problem if it keeps growing like that.
이대로 계속 성장했다간 큰일이 벌어질 거야
We must do something.
어떻게든 해야...
Did you notice that the topmost leaf of Mekaju Seijin shines when Infinity Cannon shoots?
저 무한포가 발사될 때 메카쥬 성인의 맨위에 있는 잎이 빛나는 걸 보셨나요?
No, I didn't...
아니, 몰랐는데...
What's so important about that?
잎이 빛난 게 어쨌다는 거야?
It means that the Infinity Cannon is powered by solar energy.
즉, 무한포는 태양 에너지에 의해 발사되고 있는 겁니다
So what's your point?
그러니까, 할 말이 뭐야?
It's going to need lots of energy to charge such a powerful gun.
저정도로 강력한 총이니, 상당한 양의 에너지가 필요하겠죠
So it will take some time to be charged by solar energy.
따라서, 태양 에너지를 충전하는 데 시간이 걸릴 겁니다
To shorten the time taken, it's sending the energy made by photosynthesis to the Infinity Cannon.
그 시간을 단축하기 위해 저 잎으로 합성한 에너지를 무한포에 보내고 있는 겁니다
The point is, it cannot shoot that gun continuously.
요점은, 저 총을 연속적으로 발사할 수 없으며
It doesn't take long, but it still takes some time.
약간이지만, 시간이 걸린다는 거군
Yeah. According to my observation, it takes about 10 seconds.
예, 제 관찰로는 10초 정도 걸립니다
Thus, if we manage to take that short chance...
그러니, 그 틈을 잘 이용해 공격할 수 있다면...
I see that we might have a chance to win.
우리에게 승산이 있을 지도 모른다는 거군
Change!
체인지!
Lian!
라이안!
Seems that Mekaju Seijin has appeared.
메카쥬 성인이 나타난 것 같군
Do you know that alien?
저 우주인을 알고 있나?
Yes, I do.
그래, 알고 있지
I saw it during my long journey.
긴 방랑 도중에 본 적이 있어
I saw a ruined solar system, covered by Mekaju Seijin.
메카쥬 성인에게 뒤덮혀 멸망한 태양계를 말이야
Mekaju Seijin are a plant-type machine lifeform.
메카쥬 성인은 식물 타입의 기계 생명체야
It is a machine, but it acts like a plant; it bears fruits and makes seeds.
기계지만, 마치 식물처럼 열매를 맺고 씨를 만들지
Let's say that its seed landed on some planet.
어느 혹성에 그 씨가 떨어졌다고 가정하자
When it happens, it roots on that planet and grow up to height of multiple tens of kilometers.
그렇게 되면, 녀석은 그 혹성에 뿌리를 내리고 성장하여 나무의 높이는 수십 킬로미터에 달하며
At last, they root until the planet become saturated.
최종적으론, 혹성이 포화 상태가 될 때까지 뿌리를 내려
It also covers the ground.
지상을 뒤덮어 가고 말아
Needless to say, all life on that planet got annihilated.
물론 그 별의 생물은 전멸하지
It is a truly fearsome machine lifeform.
정말 무서운 기계 생명체야
Then that'll do that too?
그럼, 저녀석은...
It'll take up the whole Earth if we don't do anything.
이대로 방치해 둔다면, 지구 전체를 뒤덮고 말겠군요?
Right. We can assume that it made the robot which was the Space Vanguard Weapon in Sargasso.
그래, 분명 녀석은 사르갓소 안에서 우주 선견(先遣) 무기인, 저 로봇을 만들었겠지
-Space Vanguard Weapon?
-Right.
-우주 선견 무기?
-그래
And it targeted this Earth.
그리고 이 지구를 타겟으로 정했겠지
Is there any way to take it down, Lian?
녀석을 해치울 방법은 없어, 라이안?
-That Infinity Cannon is definitely matchless.
-What?!
-저 무한포는 틀림없이 무적이야
-뭐야?
If I get hit directly, I'm done for.
저걸 정면으로 맞았다간, 나도 끝장이야
Of course, you guys too.
물론 너희들도 마찬가지다
However, we must stop its growth, or...
하지만, 어떻게든 녀석의 성장을 막지 않으면...
Hey, Dagwon!
이봐~ 다그온~
Hey!
여봐~
-Gaku?
-Why did you come?
-가쿠 군?
-너, 어째서 이런 곳에...
I thought you guys might be here.
역시 여기 있었구나
I heard that aliens appeared, so I ran to see you.
우주인이 나타났다고 해서, 일단 달려와 봤어
Just as I expected!
분명히 있을 거라고 생각했지!
Get lost!
남 일에는 신경 꺼!
It's dangerous here, so go back!
여기는 위험하다구, 떨어져 있어!
No way! Let me help you!
말도 안돼, 나도 있게 해 줘
Don't be stupid!
바보같은 소리 마!
Silence. We're making a tactical plan.
조용히 해, 작전 회의중이야
Tactical plan? Awesome!
적전 회의?!
짱이다~
Moments ago, instead of the place it first rooted in, it appeared somewhere different.
방금 전, 녀석은 처음 뿌리를 내린 지하가 아닌 다른 곳에서 튀어나왔습니다
Thus, we must dig up all the roots and destroy them.
그러니, 최종적으론 뿌리까지 들어가, 모두 해치워야만 합니다
To do that, we must take care of that gun robot.
그러기 위해선, 그 총 로봇을 어떻게든 처리해야 해
As long as that guy's using that, we can't be careless.
녀석이 저걸 쥐고 있는 한, 섣부른 행동은 불가능하니 말야
Right.
그렇습니다
It already grew to 100 meters.
다그 터보, 이미 거의 100미터 가까이 성장했습니다
100 meters?!
100미터라고?!
Anyway, we must get the gun robot away from Mekaju Seijin.
어쨌든 총 로봇을 메카쥬 성인에게서 떼어 놓는 게 최우선이야
But still, wherever we approach him from, it won't work if that guy shoots at us!
하지만 말야, 어디서 접근하든 녀석이 쏴 버리면 꽝이잖아
-Let's go underground.
-Underground?
-지하(地下)다
-지하?
I like this planet, dear Gundroid T96.
이 별은 마음에 드는구나, 건드로이드 T96아
Most of all, there are infinite amount of energy in the Earth.
무엇보다도, 지구에는 에너지가 무한에 가깝게 있어
Yeah! This is a good place.
응! 참 좋은 곳이구나
At this rate, in a month, we should be able to take over this planet.
이정도라면, 1개월만 지나면 이 혹성 전체를 뒤덮을 수 있겠어
Yay!
만세~
If we're going underground, it's my turn to act!
땅 속으로 접근한다면, 내가 나설 차례지!
The ground will probably be full of Mekaju Seijin's roots.
땅 속에는 메카쥬 성인의 뿌리가 잔뜩 있을 거예요
Are you okay with that?
괜찮겠습니까?
It's nothing! My Drill Liner will go through at once!
그딴 것 쯤이야!
드릴 라이너 한 방 감이라구!
It will be massive and durable.
상당히 굵고 튼튼할 거예요
Right. If we just mess around underground, our enemy might notice us.
지하에서 섣불리 행동했다간 적이 눈치챌 위험이 있어
Then why don't you all chain up?
그럼 말야, 모두 함께 이어서 가면 어때?
Chain up?
모두 함께 이어서?
Right. Why not connect the bullet trains to Drill Liner and pass through?
그래, 드릴 라이너에 신간선을 연결해서 말야 압도하는 거야
Don't joke around! Are you asking us to choo-choo around?
말도 안되는 소리 마!
기차놀이 하자는 거냐?!
I told you to go back!
정말이지...
No. He may be right.
아니, 꼭 그렇다고만은 할 수 없어
The power might be amplified enough to make an unexpected effect.
힘이 증폭되서 생각치 못한 효과가 나올지도 몰라
Are you serious?
진심이냐?!
Alright. I'll tell you the plan.
좋아, 작전을 말해 줄게
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Wow! Awesome!
우와~ 굉장하다~
Alright! Let's go!
좋아! 간다!
This is awesome! This quadruple chain sure is something!
이거 대단하구만!
4중 연결의 힘, 꽤 좋은걸!
We're about to arrive right below the body of our enemy!
슬슬 적 본체의 바로 밑에 도착합니다
We're ready, En! Ryu!
엔, 류! 이쪽 OK다!
Alright, understood!
좋아, 알았어!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Merging Fusion!
융합합체(融合合體)
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우
Shadow Dragon!
섀도우 드래곤!
-Huh?
-What is it?
-어레?
-뭐지?
Face us!
자, 간다!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
How futile!
어리석기는...!
This is nothing!
이쯤이야!
Shadow Vulcan!
섀도우 발칸!
You annoying bastards! You're going down this time.
성가신 녀석들!
이번에야말로...
Damn!
젠장!
Now!
지금이다!
Take care of the branches!
가지를 노려라!
Break Wheel!
브레이크 호일!
Armor Vulcan!
아머 발칸!
Freeze Beam!
프리즈 빔!
Rock Buster!
락 버스터!
Unforgivable!
에에이! 시끄럽다!
It hurts!
에고 아퍼!
Shit!
큰일이다!
I won't let you do that!
그렇게는 안되지!
Run away!
도망쳐라~
What are you doing?!
무슨 짓이야?!
Prepare yourself!
각오해라!
No! I'm scared!
싫어! 무섭단 말야!
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터...
Wait!
기다려!
Just a moment, Dag Fire.
기다려, 다그 파이어
Why not use this guy instead of destroying him?
이녀석을 파괴하기보다는 사용해 보는게 어때?
What are you talking about?
무슨 소리야?
Hey, you. Become the Infinity Cannon.
이봐, 너
무한포로 변형해라
Why?
왜?
If you don't want to be destroyed, do as I say.
부서지기 싫으면 말 들어라
I see. Great!
오호라... 알았어!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Alright!
좋았어!
Fire!
발사!
Why? Why won't you fire?
어째서지?
왜 안 나가는 거냐?!
The solar energy isn't enough yet.
아직 태양 에너지가 부족해서 그래
Just a moment!
조금만 기달려
What?!
뭐야?
-Aren't you ready?
-Almost there!
-아직이냐?!
-좀만 더 있으면 된다니까!
Hurry up already!
얼른 좀 해봐!
Alright! Energy charge is OK!
좋아, 에너지 충전 OK!
Alright!
좋았어!
What?!
아니?!
Stop it!
그만둬!
Don't aim Gundroid to me!
건드로이드를 이쪽에 겨냥하지마!
Everyone! Get away from him!
얘들아, 그놈에게서 떨어져!
S- stop!
그, 그만둬!
Let's go!
간다!
Infinity Cannon, fire!
무한포(無限砲), 파이어!
Awesome! It took care of the roots!
엄청나구만!
We did it!
해냈구나!
This guy surely is an awesome weapon!
이놈, 정말 대단한 병기야!
To take that gigantic tree at once...
그 엄청나게 큰 나무를 일격으로...
Then what should we do with this guy?
그럼, 이녀석을 어떻게 할까?
It surely is a dangerous guy.
확실히, 정말 위험한 녀석입니다
Expected, from an alien made by such a strong alien.
그정도로 힘겨웠던 우주인이 만든 로봇이야
I think we have no choice but to destroy him.
난 파괴할 수밖에 없다고 생각해
No!
싫어~
Don't destroy me!
파괴하지 말라구~
Bye-bye!
바이바이~
Shit!
아뿔싸!
What speed!
젠장, 엄청 빠르구만!
I'll take care of that gun robot.
저 총 로봇은 내가 어떻게든 할게
You can go back.
넌 돌아가라
What did you say?
뭐라고?
Don't worry. Please leave it to me.
걱정하지마, 내게 맡겨
I'm hungry.
배고프구만
Say, we didn't eat anything since this morning!
그러고보니, 아침부터 아무것도 못 먹었구만
I wonder where Lian went.
라이안은 어디까지 간 걸까요?
He came back.
음? 돌아왔다
Change!
체인지!
Me too! Change!
나도 체인지!
Lian?
라이안?
Hey, what's up with that robot kid?
이봐! 어떻게 된 거냐, 그 로봇은?
Weren't you going to destroy it?
부수는 거 아니었어?
You shouldn't do that!
그런 짓 하면 안돼!
What?
뭐야?
Right! It's miserable to be destroyed!
그래! 부숴버린다니, 불쌍하다구
Everyone.
얘들아
About this gun robot...
이 총 로봇에 대한 건데...
wouldn't you let me to take care of this guy?
어때? 내가 돌보게 해 주지 않을래?
Take care?
돌본다고?
This guy is made as a weapon, but it is still a robot.
이녀석은 무기로써 만들어졌지만, 로봇에 지나지 않아
It was just following the orders of Mekaju Seijin.
단지 그 메카쥬 성인의 명령을 따랐을 뿐이야
I am a robot lifeform too.
나도 기계 생명체야
I cannot just destroy.
그냥 파괴해 버릴 수는 없어
Can we trust him, even if you take care of him?
네가 맡는다고 해도, 믿을 수 있겠어?
Yes. This guy doesn't know anything about Earth.
그래, 이녀석은 지구에 대해 아무것도 몰라
I'll teach him as a brother, and make him a comrade of Dagwon by any means!
내가 동생으로 삼아, 교육을 해서 어쨌든, 한사람의 다그온의 동료로 만들어 보이겠어
That's right!
그 말대로야!
Will it work?
잘 될까?
Alright, understood. We'll leave him to you.
좋아, 알았어
네게 맡길게
Thank you.
고맙다
Then that robot will be a new comrade of Dagwon, right?
그럼 그 로봇, 다그온의 새로운 동료가 되는 거네?
That's right.
그래
What's his name?
이름이 뭐야?
Right, what's your name?
맞아, 너 이름이 뭐였지?
I am Gundroid T96.
난 건드로이드 T96
Gu- Gun... what?
거, 건... 뭐라고?
We need a name easier to pronounce.
좀 더 부르기 쉬운 이름이 필요하겠구만
I see.
그렇군
Your name will be Gunkid from now on.
네 이름은 「건키드」다
Gunkid?
건키드?
Gunkid? It's a weird name.
건키드? 이상한 이름이네
It means a new life in the language of my planet.
우리 별 말로
「새로운 생명」이라는 뜻이야
Gunkid, huh..
건키드라...
I don't know if I can trust you, but...
조금 못 믿겠지만...
Welcome aboard.
뭐, 한번 잘 해 보라구
-Now, Gunkid, let's go.
-Yes! I'll follow you, uncle.
-자 건키드, 가자
-응! 나, 아저씨랑 갈래
It's Lian. Despite the look, I'm still young.
라이안이라고 불러
이래뵈도 아직 젊다구
Do I look like an uncle?
아저씨는 아니잖아?
Hey! Wait for me, Lian!
앗! 기다려, 라이안~!
Will he be all right?
괜찮겠습니까, 져너석?
Look at the power of that Infinity Cannon. In good hands, it will become a powerful comrade.
저 무한포의 위력. 잘만 사용한다면 우리 강력한 아군이 될 거야
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Are you okay with this, Lian? How can you possibly teach Gunkid?
괜찮겠어, 라이안? 건키드를 교육하겠다고 선언하다니...
-Keep quiet and leave it to me.
-But look!
-아무말 말고 내게 맡겨다오!
-하지만 봐라!
Gunkid shot the Vulcan cannon inside Dag Base!
건키드 녀석, 다그 베이스 안에서 발칸포를 쏴댔다구
That's serious! I must take...
이거 큰일이군! 어떻게든 손을 써야...
Not the time for that! A big tomato came to attack!
그러고 있을 때가 아니야! 거대한 토마토가 습격해 왔어!
What he heck is this?!
대체 뭐래냐, 이건!?
Could it be Ark Seijin's new strategy?!
설마, 아크 성인의 새로운 작전인가!?
Bye-bye
Lian
PS. En is a nerd
안녕
라이안
엔 바보
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Oath of the Infinity Cannon!
다음회 용자지령 다그온
맹세의 무한포
Gunkid pointed his gun at me!
건키드가 나에게 총구를 들이대다니!!
Oath of the Infinity Cannon
맹세의 무한포